<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: howto | HFI 科学狂人官网--Mad Scientists Official Site]]></title>
  <link href="http://hfims.github.com/blog/categories/howto/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://hfims.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-06T20:00:27+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://hfims.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rongcui Dong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Activity 1--Smokebomb]]></title>
    <link href="http://hfims.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/howto-smokebomb.en/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-19T12:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://hfims.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/howto-smokebomb.en</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="{%%20post_url%202012-09-19-howto-smokebomb.zh%20%}">中文版</a></p>

<p>This is the whole process of making a simple smokebomb.</p>

<p>Materials:</p>

<p>KNO<sub>3</sub>, normal sugar, Karo syrup, tap water, paper box</p>

<p>Tools:</p>

<p>Pot, gas stove, salt, glass bowl, stirring rod, asbestos-free wire gauze, lighter, 50mL volumetric cylinder,
balance<del>, hand</del>, gloves, iron wire, tongs.</p>

<p>Procedures:</p>

<ol>
<li>Use the balance to measure 60 grams of KNO<sub>3</sub> and 40 grams of 
sugar and put them into the glass bowl</li>
<li>Add 30mL of water</li>
<li>Put a layer of salt on the pot</li>
<li>Put the bowl on the salt</li>
<li>Put the pot on the stove, use the smallest fire to heat and use the 
stirring rod to stir
<li>When boiled, put about 1mL of syrup into the bowl
<li>If there are lots of bubbles, put out the fire and continue to stir. When 
bubbles stop producing, start the fire again
<li>About 40 minutes later, there are lots of solid, speed up the stirring
<li>When the surface of solid look smooth, start testing: put out the fire, 
continue to stir, and use tongs to take a little piece of solid and wait for it 
to cool down. If the solid can be cracked, then the fuel is done.
<li>When the solid in the bowl is cooler, use <del>hands</del> gloves to remove 
the solid and place into the paper box
<li>Wait until fully cooled down.
<li>Done!
</ol>


<p>This is using recrystalization, so the quality of fuel is VERY good. If use the
lighter to heat the iron wire and poke the wire into the piece of fuel used to
test, it burns quickly and releases lots of smoke and remains nothing.
Great effects!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
